JASPER KATZBAN DESIGNER & ENGINEER

CONTACT

Email

jasperkatzban@gmail.com

Phone

(845) 667-6760

Portfolio

jasperkatzban.com

Github

@jasperkatzban

SKILLS

Creative

Adobe Suite, Figma, Sketch, Framer, Blender, Logic Pro, Final Cut Pro

Software

Python, C++, JS, React, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Processing

Hardware

Verilog, Assembly, KiCad, LTSpice, SolidWorks

COURSES

Design Nature

Software Design

Modeling & Simulation

Computer Architecture

Intro to Microelectronic Circuits

Sensors, Instruments & Measurement

Quantitative Engineering Analysis

I enjoy exploring the intersection of design and engineering to create meaningful solutions for people in need. Through my interests in experience design, digital media, and software, I seek to bring more of those 'woah!' moments into the world.

EXPERIENCE

OCCaM Lab at Olin College - Jan 2021 to Present

Implementing mobile analytics pipeline using Swift, Firebase, and Python to aid UX research on an AR navigation app helping blind and low vision individuals.

Freelance Design Services - 2018 to Present

Providing web design & development, content creation, and branding consultation services to non-profits and startups in the sustainability and social impact fields.

Lucky Eight Media - 2018 to 2020

Led design and marketing at an early stage lead-gen startup focusing on lowering consumer insurance rates. Expanded web lead-gen channels and designed data analytics product frontend.

PROJECTS

Senatr: Gamified Lobbying - Fall 2020

Helped to make an educational mobile game focused on lobbying and climate legislation, creating storyboards, visuals, and UI prototypes.

The Archives of Asterion - Spring & Summer 2020

Worked with award-winning creative studio Third Rail Projects to develop and publish a theatrical webVR experience. Created 3D assets and scripted gameplay and graphics in A-Frame and Three.js.

VR for Seniors @ Rendever - 2017 to 2018

Interned at an MIT spinoff utilizing VR to improve quality of life for seniors with dementia. Conducted data-driven UX research studies, which won awards at local Intel and Regeneron science fairs.

EDUCATION

Olin College of Engineering

BS Engineering: Design & Computing (2019-2023)

Recipient of 4-yr 50% Olin Merit Scholarship | GPA: 3.7

Westchester Community College

Gap Year Studies (2018)

Courses: Manufacturing I & II, Intro to CAD | GPA: 4.0

MIT Launch

Led design and fabrication of a 3D printer monitoring system at a competitive youth startup accelerator run by MIT Sloan.